# Mambo-Mary

+237676292112

mamboanye6@gmail.com

Gender: Female Date of birth: 03/03/1997 Nationality: Cameroonian

### PERSONAL STATEMENT

A result-driven young professional with an interest in food and development economics. Motivated to protect and solve economic development crises in developing countries. Seeks to bridge the gap between research findings and practical applications through knowledge acquisition.

#### FORMAL EDUCATION

#### **MSc. Economics Science**

Faculty of Economics and Management Sciences, University of Bamenda, Cameroon, 2017-2019 Second Class Upper Honours, Very Good

### **BSc.** Economics Science

Faculty of Social and Management Sciences, University of Buea, Cameroon, 2013 – 2016 Second Class Upper Honours, Very Good

# DIPET 1 (Teacher diploma of technical education first degree)

Higher Technical Teachers' Training College Bambili, 2017-2019 Second Class Upper Honours, Very Good

### **FURTHER EDUCATION**

#### **Introduction to Gender Based Violence Eradication Platforms in Schools**

United Nations for Children Fund (UNICEF), 2023

Specialized in service delivery, enabling environment, emergency response against gender-based violence in Cameroon.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Teacher**

Government Technical High School, Manengole, 2019-Present

- Planned Economics, Mathematics, and Management lesson notes.
- Adopted varied teaching methods for positive learning outcomes.
- Enhanced social abilities and learning skills among students.

## **Livelihood Support Officer**

Women in Action Against Gender Based Violence, 2019-2020

Responsible for technical planning, supervision, monitoring, and reporting of public awareness activities in Nguti community.

### **Marketing Intern**

CAMPOST, 2017 - 2019

- Developed tools for collecting data such as surveys and polls.
- Analyzed data to identify consumer trends.
- Created graphic representations of data.

# **LANGUAGES**

English: Very Good (all skills)
French: Good (all skills)

## **SKILLS**

- Leadership and Interpersonal skills.
- Excellent command of office suite, good command of statistical software (SPSS, STATA).
- Graphics design, Teamwork, Time management, Adaptability, Fashion designing.

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Dissertation: Role of women empowerment in Economic Development in Cameroon

Seminars: The Role of educational planning in agricultural development

Membership: Cameroon Teachers Trade Union, Youth Development Network Club